essexapartmenthomes.com 2019-10-14

# Privacy Policy | Essex Apartment Homes

**Privacy Policy**

 _(effective January 2019)_

Essex Property Trust, Inc. (“Essex,” “we,” “our,” or “us”) is a real estate investment trust (REIT) that acquires, develops, redevelops, and manages multifamily apartment communities in California and Washington.  This Privacy Policy describes our data practices regarding information that could be used to identify you or that is associated with information that identifies you (“Personal Information”). This Privacy Policy applies to Personal Information that we gather or collect via the Web Site, as well as to Personal Information collected offline by Essex.  It does not apply to any Personal Information collected by third party web sites not operated by Essex.  Except as set forth in this Privacy Policy, Essex will not share, sell, or rent individual Personal Information with anyone without your advance permission or unless ordered by a court of law.

 **WHAT INFORMATION DOES ESSEX GATHER ABOUT ME?**

 **Personal Information You Provide**

 _General_

We collect certain Personal Information you voluntarily provide in order to deliver services.  For example, you may be asked to provide Personal Information such as name, email address, and phone number, when requesting a tour of an Essex apartment community.  If you do not provide this Personal Information, we may not be able to assist you in scheduling a tour of an Essex apartment community.  We may collect your email address so that we can send you information you have requested. We may use your email address to inform you about current events or to send you updates regarding information that was previously sent to you.

Essex works with third party web site operators to provide services such as online rental applications, resident services, and investor relations information (“Portal Sites”).  When you input Personal Information to one of Essex’s Portal Sites, you are providing that information to a third party.  Essex’s Portal Sites may utilize framing techniques to make it appear that the user is still on the Web Site when the user is actually on a Portal Site.  For example, if you are on a page that has the look and feel of [www.essexapartmenthomes.com](http://www.essexapartmenthomes.com/), but the URL listed in your browser is a different URL than www.essexapartmenthomes.com, then know that any information you provide is being collected by this third party and not governed by this Privacy Policy. 

When you leave the Web Site and are transferred to a Portal Site, you may be notified that you are no longer on the Essex Web Site.  You should carefully review the privacy policy and terms of use for any Portal Site before using and providing Personal Information through a Portal Site.  The operators of such Portal Sites may share the information you enter with Essex.  You should carefully review this Privacy Policy to see how Essex uses information you enter through the Web Site or through any Portal Sites.

 _On-Site_

In order to submit a rental application online for one of Essex’s apartment communities, you will be redirected to a Portal Site operated by On-Site.  On-Site will request certain Personal Information from you in order to process your rental application.  This information may include your name, mailing address, email address, date of birth, social security number, and other identifying information.  On-Site collects this information to process your rental application and communicate your regarding your rental application. You should review On-Site’s data collection and sharing practices prior to providing any Personal Information to On-Site.

 _Rentcafé_

Resident Portal is run and operated by Rentcafé.  Rentcafé provides certain resident services such as payment processing, maintenance support and requests, and other technical support.  Rentcafé operates bulletin boards and chat rooms, and offers promotions, contests, or sweepstakes.  Rentcafé collects certain Personal Information in order to provide you with these services and may require the creation of an account to access these services.  You should review Rentcafé’s privacy policy prior to providing any information to Rentcafé.

 _iCIMS_

Essex uses a third party to process applications for employment, iCIMS.  iCIMS collects Personal Information when you fill out an application for employment at Essex.  This information may include your name, address, email address, phone number, date of birth, employment history, educational history, and other Personal Information that is or may be relevant the position to which you are applying.  iCIMS collects this information to and shares this information with Essex so that Essex can evaluate your application for employment and communicate with you about the position or positions you are seeking.

 **Automatically Collected Data**

When you visit our Web Site or Portal Sites, we or our third-party Portal Site operators may collect information to administer the Web Site and analyze its usage.

Examples of this information include:

  * Your IP address.
  * The kind of browser or computer you use.
  * Number of links you click within the site.
  * State or country from which you accessed the site.
  * Date and time of your visit.
  * Name of your Internet service provider.
  * Web page you linked to our site from.
  * Pages you viewed on the site.

This information is collected to help us administer and operate the Web Site, better understand how users interact with and access the Web Site and Portal Sites, and understand the types of users access the Web Site and Portal Sites. 

 **HOW DOES ESSEX USE PERSONAL INFORMATION?**

 **Business Purposes**

We collect and use Personal Information for the following business purposes:

(1) to provide you with services or process transactions that you have requested;

(2) to communicate with you regarding information, features or offers that we believe will be of interest to you;

(3) to respond to your questions or other requests;

(4) to contact you with regard to the Web Site or Portal Sites;

(5) to process any applications, payments or changes to your account information;

(6) to process other information or Personal Information that you submit through the Web Site or Portal Sites;

(7) to conduct user surveys;

(8) to contact you regarding a sweepstakes, contest or promotion in which you have participated,

(9) to evaluate your application for employment; and

(10) to fulfill other purposes disclosed at the time you provide your Personal Information.

We may also use the information you provide to improve the Web Site or Essex’s services, to customize your experience on the Web Site or Portal Sites, to serve you specific content, or for other business purposes.

We may use the contact information you provide to communicate with you through email and other means, including mobile text messages, telephone calls, and push notifications. If you provide your telephone number, you agree that we may contact that number even if it is registered on a corporate, state, or national Do Not Call Registry.

If you are purchasing a service, we will request financial information. Any financial information we collect is used only to bill you for the services you purchased. If you purchase by credit card, this information may be forwarded to your credit card provider. For other types of registrations, we will ask for the relevant information. You may also be asked to disclose Personal Information to us so that we may provide online technical support and troubleshooting.

 **Sharing with Third Parties**

We may share your Personal Information with third parties who perform services on our behalf or on behalf of the owner of one of our properties and who may use this information for their own purposes, including sending advertising to you.  This includes, without limitation, third parties that send communications, process payments, analyze data, assist with utility billing or renter's insurance, provide credit checks, resident screening, or collection services, manage package deliveries, provide marketing and advertising services, including marketing analytics, to Essex, or create, host and/or provide customer service on our behalf. These third parties may have access to certain Personal Information in order to provide these services to us or on our behalf.  We also may share Personal Information with our business partners in order to provide services and offerings to you, and certain aggregated demographic information that does not identify you personally with our business partners regarding the users of our websites.

For more information about a third party service provider, please contact us via email at [privacy@essex.com](mailto:privacy@essex.com).

Essex may also disclose Personal Information we collect from you to third parties in order to:

  * Fulfill your service requests for services,
  * Protect ourselves from liability,
  * Protect the safety and security of Essex and its users,
  * Respond to legal process or comply with law, or
  * Provide information in connection with a merger, acquisition, or liquidation of our company.

 **Affiliated and Subsidiary Companies**

We may share Personal Information with our affiliated or subsidiary companies who use Personal Information for business purposes related to your tenancy or to process any application, request, inquiry, or other information or Personal Information you submit via the Web Site. This includes the owner of any community where you submit an application or where you lease, as well as the management company for such community.

 **COOKIES**

A cookie is a small text file that is saved in a user’s browser when you access our Web Site. We may link the information we store in cookies to any Personal Information you submit while on our Web Site.

We use both “session” cookies and “persistent” cookies.  We use session cookies to make it easier for you to navigate our Web Site. A session cookie expires when you close your browser. A persistent cookie remains on your hard drive for an extended period of time.  You can remove persistent cookies by following directions provided in your Internet browser’s help file.

We set a persistent cookie to store your passwords, so you don’t have to enter it more than once. Persistent cookies also enable us to track and target the interests of our users to enhance the experience on our Web Site and other Web sites.

If you reject cookies, you may still use our Web Site, but your ability to use some areas of our Web Site, such as saving properties, will be limited.

Some of our business partners (e.g., advertisers) may use cookies on our Web Site. For example, on occasion an advertiser may run a banner campaign on our Web Site.  We have no access to or control over these cookies.  This privacy statement covers the use of cookies by this Web Site only and does not cover the use of cookies by any business partners or advertisers on our Web Site or other Essex web sites.  See the “Third Party Advertisers” and “Links to Other Sites” sections of this Privacy Policy below for more information.

We use Google Analytics, Google AdWords, Google Tag Manager, Crazy Egg, and New Relic on the Web Site to collect non-personally identifiable data, such as your IP address, your internets service provider, the web page you linked to our Web Site from, and other clicking and browsing behavior, to analyze how users use the Web Site, and to provide targeted advertisements to you on our Web Site.  You may opt out of some of these tracking services.

 **CLEAR GIFS (WEB BEACONS)**

We may employ a software technology called clear gifs (a.k.a. Web Beacons) that help us better manage content on our Web Site by informing us what content is effective. Clear gifs are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies, and are used to track the online movements of Web users. In contrast to cookies, which are stored on a user’s computer hard drive, clear gifs are embedded invisibly on Web pages and are about the size of the period at the end of this sentence. We may tie the information gathered by clear gifs to our customers’ Personal Information. We may use clear gifs in our HTML-based emails to let us know which emails have been opened by recipients. This allows us to gauge the effectiveness of certain communications and the effectiveness of our marketing campaigns.

 **THIRD PARTY ADVERTISERS**

The ads appearing on this Web Site or other Essex web sites, if any, may be delivered to users by third-party advertising companies. Third-party advertising companies may use cookies and clear gifs on this Web Site, which allow it to recognize a user’s cookie when a user visits this Web Site and other Web sites. The companies serve their ads from their own web sites, independently from Essex. These companies may use non-personally identifiable information (e.g., click stream information, web browser type, time and date, subject of advertisements clicked or scrolled over) during your visits to the Web Site and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services likely to be of interest to you. The information that the third-party advertising companies collect and share through this technology is governed by the privacy policies of those third parties. We encourage you to read the privacy statements of each and every web site that you visit that collects personally identifiable information.

 **HOW WE RESPOND TO “DO NOT TRACK” SIGNALS**

Our systems do not respond to browser “Do Not Track” signals, but several of our business partners who utilize cookies, Web Beacons, or other tracking technologies on the Web Site may enable you to opt out of certain of their cookies, Web Beacons, and other tracking technologies and the tailoring of advertisements to your interests. We also provide you with additional tools to opt out of certain communications from us.  You can learn about this in the “Your Choices” section of this Privacy Policy.

 **AMAZON UNIVERSAL LOCKER, PARCEL PENDING, LLC OR OTHER PARCEL LOCKER PROVIDER**

Essex has partnered with Amazon and Parcel Pending to install Parcel Lockers in some of Essex’s apartment communities.  These universal lockers allow for deliveries and returns of packages from and to Amazon and other third parties in a dedicated storage unit.  Essex may share the names, addresses, and email addresses of residents in those apartment communities with Amazon Universal Lockers, Parcel Pending or other parcel locker vendors to facilitate the registration process for the universal locker.  You will be contacted to register for the universal locker when you first receive a package.  We encourage you to read Amazon’s Privacy Notice and Conditions of Use and Parcel Pending’s FAQs and Privacy Policy prior to registering.

 **FACEBOOK CONNECT OR OTHER OPENID PROVIDER**

We may offer you the ability to log in to our Web Site using sign-in services such as Facebook Connect or another Open ID provider, which are third-party credentialing services. These services will authenticate your identity and provide you the option to share certain Personal Information with us such as your name and email address to pre-populate our sign-up form. Services like Facebook Connect give you the option to post information about your activities on this Web Site to your profile page to share with others within your network. Any posting outside of the Web Site is governed by the privacy policies of the posting service and we encourage you to read the privacy statements of each and every posting service that collects personally identifiable information.

 **LINKS TO OTHER SITES**

This privacy statement applies only to Personal Information collected by this Web Site.  This Web Site contains links to other sites that are not owned or controlled by Essex. Please be aware that Essex is not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites.  We encourage you to be aware when you leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every web site that collects personally identifiable information.

 **SHARE THIS**

When you use “Share This” to bookmark and share our products and Web Site, you will be taken to a third party site.  These third party sites’ privacy policies govern the collection and use of the information collected on those sites.

 **CHILD PROTECTION AND PRIVACY**

Essex does not knowingly seek to collect or maintain Personal Information or other information from children under the age of 13.  We will use commercially reasonable efforts to delete any Personal Information or other information later determined to be provided by a child under the age of 13.  Use of the Web Site by children under the age of 13 is not permitted.  If you become aware that a child has provided Personal Information through our Web Site, please email us at [privacy@essex.com](mailto:privacy@essex.com).  

 **YOUR CHOICES**

In general, you may browse the Web Site or a Portal Site without providing Personal Information.  However, if you choose not to provide certain Personal Information through this Web Site or a Portal Site, Essex may not be able to provide certain services or process certain of your requests. You may not be able to submit an application for employment, may not be able to access resident services online, or otherwise use all of the features and products that Essex offers through this Web Site or a Portal Site.

Depending on the functionality associated with the Web Site feature or Portal Site you are using, you may be able to update certain of your Personal Information on the Web Site. If you no longer wish to receive marketing emails from us, you can opt out of these communications by clicking on the “unsubscribe” link included in those emails. Please see the “Contact Us” section of this Privacy Policy for information about how to contact us with questions.

 **LEGAL REQUIREMENTS AND LAW ENFORCEMENT**

We may disclose Personal Information when we believe in good faith that the law requires it; at the request of governmental authorities conducting an audit or investigation; pursuant to a court order, subpoena, or discovery request in litigation; to verify or enforce compliance with our Terms of Use or other agreements or policies governing the Web Site and applicable laws, rules, and regulations; or whenever we believe disclosure is necessary to limit our legal liability or to protect or enforce the rights, interests, or safety of the Web Site, its users or other third parties. We also reserve the right to report to law enforcement agencies any activities that we, in good faith, believe to be unlawful.

 **SWEEPSTAKES AND PROMOTIONS.**

If you choose to enter a sweepstakes, contest or other promotion, your personal information may be disclosed to third parties in connection with the administration of such promotion, including, without limitation, in connection with winner selection, prize fulfillment, and as required by law, such as on a winners list. Also, by entering a promotion, you are agreeing to the official rules that govern that promotion, which may contain specific requirements of you, including, except where prohibited by law, allowing the sponsor(s) of the promotion to use your name, voice and/or likeness in advertising or marketing associated with the promotion.

 **NOTICE TO CALIFORNIA RESIDENTS/YOUR CALIFORNIA PRIVACY RIGHTS**

To opt out of sharing your Personal Information with third parties for their direct marketing purposes, please email Essex at [privacy@essex.com](mailto:privacy@essex.com) and clearly state your request, including your name, mailing address, email address and phone number.  Please see the “Your Choices” section of this Privacy Policy for additional information.

In addition, California Civil Code Section § 1798.83 permits users of our Site that are California residents to request certain information regarding our disclosure of Personal Information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. To make such a request, please contact us using the information provided at the end of this policy.

 **SECURITY**

Essex will take reasonable steps to secure the Personal Information you agree to provide via the Web Site.  Please note that no transmission of Personal Information over the Internet or the subsequent electronic storage of this information can be absolutely guaranteed to be free from unauthorized use or access.  Before submitting any Personal Information via the Web Site, please be aware of these inherent risks and know that you do so at your own risk.

 **INFORMATION RETENTION**

Please note that in accordance with our routine corporate record-keeping practices, we may store, transfer or delete records that contain your Personal Information. We are under no obligation to store such information indefinitely and disclaim any liability arising out of, or related to, the destruction of such information.

 **CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY STATEMENT**

We reserve the right to alter, modify, update, add to, subtract from or otherwise change this Privacy Policy at any time, which will become effective as of posting on the Web Site.  We encourage you to periodically review this privacy statement to stay informed about how we are helping to protect the Personal Information we collect.

 **JURISDICTION**

The Web Site is operated in the United States of America (U.S.) and is only intended for use by individuals accessing it from the U.S.  If you are located in another jurisdiction, then please be aware that any Personal Information you elect to supply will be transferred from your current location to the U.S. – to our servers, offices, and/or to the third parties described above (see “How Does Essex Use Personal Information?”), and be subject to U.S. laws regarding data privacy and collection, which may be less stringent than or otherwise different from the laws in effect in the country in which you are located.  By using this Web Site or by voluntarily providing us with your Personal Information, you acknowledge and agree with your Personal Information being processed and transferred as described above.

 **CONTACT US**

If you have any questions regarding our Privacy Policy, please contact us at [privacy@essex.com](mailto:privacy@essex.com).
